A Guide to the Isle of Wight County (Va.) Deed Books, 1688-1793
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Isle of Wight County (Va.) Deed Books, 1688-1793
The Library of Virginia
Barcode numbers 1146546-1146559/Isle of Wight County (Va.) Reels 2-9
14 v. (6479 p.); 7 microfilm reels (7209 images)
Isle of Wight County (Va.) Circuit Court.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These items came to the Library of Virginia of Virginia in a shipment of court papers from Isle of Wight County.
Historical Information
Isle of Wight was formed in 1634 (original shire). Part of Nanesmond County was added in 1769. Previous names Warrosquyoake from 1634 to 1637.
Scope and Content
Deed books, 1688-1793, of Isle of Wight County Court. The deed books record the name of the grantor and grantee, the residence of both individuals and the description of property being sold or transferred. Deed Book No. 1, 1688-1704 has order book information (1693-1695) and Deed Book No. 14, 1757-1781 also has order book information (1755-1757). The order book records all matters brought before the court when it was in session. It provides a synopsis of cases in a neater, more organized form. The volumes are indexed; more rarely, there is a comprehensive index. A wide variety of information is found in the order book including: deeds, chancery causes, judgments, records of legal disputes heard before the county court, and road orders.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Additional Isle of Wight Records can be found on microfilm at the Library of Virginia. Consult A Guide to Virginia County and City Records On Microfilm found on the Library of Virginia web site.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Isle of Wight County (Va.) Circuit Court.
Geographical Names:
Isle of Wight County (Va.) -- History.
Genre and Form Terms:
Deeds -- Virginia -- Isle of Wight County.; Land records -- Virginia -- Isle of Wight County.; Local government records -- Virginia -- Isle of Wight County.
Contents List
- Deed Book #1 and Orders 1688-1704;1693-1695 (Barcode 1146546)
- Deed Book #5 Part 1 1736-1741 (Barcode 1146547)
- Deed Book #5 Part 2 1736-1741 (Barcode 1146548)
- Deed Book #6 1741-1744 (Barcode 1146549)
- Deed Book #9 1744-1747 (Barcode 1146553)
- Deed Book #8 1744-1747 (Barcode 1146552)
- Deed Book #7 Part 1 1744-1747 (Barcode 1146550)
- Deed Book #7 Part 2 1744-1747 (Barcode 1146551)
- Deed Book #14 and Orders 1755-1757; 1757-1781 (Barcode 1146557)
- Deed Book #10 1758-1762 (Barcode 1146554)
- Deed Book #13 1761-1765 (Barcode 1146556)
- Deed Book #11 1761-1765 (Barcode 1146555)
- Deed Book #15 1782-1786 (Barcode 1146558)
- Deed Book #16 1786-1793 (Barcode 1146559)